hey guys I finally did it I published
the book it came out fool's errand
time to end the war in Afghanistan it's
at fool's errand dot u.s. fool's errand
dot u.s. it's on Amazon and paperback
and in Kindle and check it out last
night I got a brand new blurb from
Colonel Douglas McGregor he says he
recommended it to be part of the
coursework at the army command and
General Staff College that's how much he
liked it great read vitally important
brilliant achievement he said so check
that out fool's errand dot u.s. whoa is
the improvement of investment climates
by other means clouds of its for dummies
[Music]
the Scott Horton show taking out Saddam
Hussein turned out to be a pretty good
deal they hate our freedoms we're
dealing with Hitler revisited we
couldn't wait for that cold war to be
over quickly because we can go and play
with our toys in the sand go and play
with our toys in the sand
no nation could preserve freedom in the
myths of continual warfare
today I authorized the Armed Forces
United States in military action in
Libya that action has now begun when the
president desert that means that it is
not only all right you guys Scott Horton
Show check out the full archives at
Scott Horton org 4500 something of them
there for you going back to 2003 the
book is fool's errand time to end the
war in Afghanistan you find that at
fool's errand dot us and follow me on
Twitter at Scott Wharton Show
all right introducing John Kiriakou he
was CIA during the torture era and did
30 months in prison but not for
torturing anybody but for verifying the
names of CIA torturers to a reporter
he's the only CIA officer held
accountable during that entire thing and
it was for telling the truth about it
not for participating in it and check
this out I'm so excited about this I
mean obviously I haven't had a chance to
read it yet but I just saw this headline
last week it's Joseph Hickman and John
Kiriakou together the convenient
terrorist Abu Zubaydah this is so
important you guys you know of course in
this audience are familiar Joseph
Hickman is the Guantanamo guard who blew
the whistle about the murder of three
men at the CIA secret camp no or Penny
Lane sight down there at Guantanamo Bay
back in 2006 and the other Scott Horton
the international human rights lawyer
from Harper's and Columbia has written a
lot of great stories about that and then
so now these two together Kiriakou and
Hickman together with a book all about
Abu Zubaydah and Abu Zubaydah we all
remember was the poster boy for of
course we torture people we love
torturing people we gotta torture people
we don't torture people though but yeah
we do and when we do we do it because of
guys like Abu Zubaydah and then
according to Ron Suskind when
CIA director George Tenet told George W
Bush that actually yet turns out this
guy's not really al-qaeda and it's not
really that big of a deal that Bush said
I said he was important you're not going
to make me lose face on this are you
George and so that was why they
continued to pretend that Abu Zubaydah
deserved to be tortured needed to be
tortured that good information was
gained from his torture not just lies
about Saddam Hussein
welcome to the show John Kiriakou how
are you doing thank you Scott I'm very
happy to be with you again tell me how
many different lies about Saddam Hussein
did Abu Zubaydah tell under torture oh
my gosh you know this is really the this
is really the crux of the whole matter
isn't it the Abu Zubaydah was not the
number three in al-qaeda not only that
Abu Zubaydah never even joined al-qaeda
and the CIA in the White House were
trumpeting the notion that not only was
he the number three in al-qaeda but that
he was instrumental in the planning of
the September 11th attacks that was just
simply a lie and then when we were
looking for justification for the Iraq
war the administration pointed at Abu
Zubaydah and at Khalid Sheikh Mohammed
and said that they were the ones who who
arranged or organized the contact
between al-qaeda and and Saddam Hussein
absolutely preposterous on its face
al-qaeda hated Saddam Hussein as much as
they hated us Saddam Hussein was a
secular leader whether we liked his
politics or not there was nothing Muslim
about him he was hated by al-qaeda and
vice versa as much as we were and so
really if you look back to that period
from September 11th 2001 until the end
of the Bush administration everything
was based on a line yeah you know let me
ask you this I mean this is just sort of
an opinion speculation question not
really a factual or a yes/no type
question but why do you think that they
bothered really torturing lies out of
zubeida and out of shake all Libya and
there may have been others I don't know
off the top my head of others who were
made to implicate Saddam Hussein why was
that better than just making up lies
like an example the the lies that
al-libi told that saddam had trained
them how to make chemical weapons and
had trained them how to hijack airplanes
and all these things I mean why not just
pretend he said that or that somebody
did you know that's a great question
and I'm not even sure I have an answer
for you I think and this is gonna be
this is gonna sound very sad but I think
that there was a group during the Bush
administration a group made up of
neoconservatives and I mean Democrats as
well as Republicans remember Richard
Perle is still a registered Democrat
that's right who just loved the idea of
torture because they loved the idea of
getting tough remember when I was first
approached and asked if I wanted to be
trained in these torture techniques well
what it was was I was I was at the CIA
and a senior a senior counterterrorism
center officer approached me and said
hey I'm glad I ran into you do you want
to be trained in the use of enhanced
interrogation techniques and I had never
heard that term before
so I said what's that mean and instead
of explaining it directly
he very excitedly said we're gonna start
getting rough with these guys and so I
think maybe that that was really a part
of it it was it was that they wanted to
they wanted to be Cowboys they wanted to
be tough guys Trump said right Trump
said look if it doesn't work they
deserve it anyway
it's their punishment it's that attitude
that got us to the situation that we
were in and then yeah so this is the
thing too is what a red herring that it
doesn't work it doesn't work sure it
works it works great and it you know in
fact well I mean I don't want to
oversimplify I was reading this piece at
salon.com
where where you guys are kind of
introducing your new book here the road
to torture how the CIA's enhanced
interrogation techniques became legal
after 9/11 and you guys really do a
great job of explaining what the
previous interrogation techniques were
not just the FBI's options but the CIA's
options and how they considered you know
what they considered to be
tried-and-true methods of interrogation
but it seems like
I mean maybe this is just hindsight you
know kind of thing or or you know
whatever mischaracterization but it sort
of seems like when they're saying that
torture doesn't work because it results
in false information that what they were
really saying is torture works great for
getting false information and we need
some and that maybe that was why they
did it in the first place I mean I'm
trying to picture a CIA guy torturing
zubeida or a Libby or something and
saying you know tell me about Saddam and
then they go oh yes Saddam yeah he
taught me how to make chemical weapons
and I'm trying to picture a CIA guy
believing this rather than smiling that
he's succeeded in torturing the lies he
needed out of this schmuck exactly
exactly right I think that's exactly
right I told ABC News way back when in
2007 when I first went public on this
thing that if you torture a guy long
enough he's gonna confess to kidnapping
the Lindbergh baby I mean if that's your
point if your point is to get him to
just admit to something anything then
sure sure torture works all right now so
tell us a bunch of stories about how all
this started cuz you were in on the
nabbing of Khalid Sheikh Mohammed Ramzi
bin al-shibh and or all Zubaydah I get
this all mixed up there in the early
days of the terror war right yeah I'll
correct you on that one yeah I was the
chief of counterterrorism operations in
Pakistan post 9/11 and so I led a series
of raids in March of 2002 that resulted
in the capture of a Zubaydah we caught
him that night and I'm not allowed to
say the exact number but many dozens of
other al-qaeda fighters including some
senior people
I ran spurred to a different job inside
the CIA when I got back that summer of
2002 so Remzi been a ship in Khalid
Sheikh Mohammed happened oh six or eight
weeks after I had switched over okay I
wish I could take credit for those guys
but no I'm sorry I got that wrong I was
going from memory instead of rereading
this morning make sure all right but now
so well once you got back to the States
then what was your job cuz I thought I
had remembered that you were commenting
pretty specifically about what had
happened in Thailand with these guys
right
yeah my job was to be the executive
assistant to the CIA's deputy director
for operations and so I was his morning
brief and the directors morning briefer
for the following year and in that
position because because you're the
deputy directors right-hand guy on all
the reporting worldwide I had access to
literally everything that was coming in
from every CIA station and base around
the world and that's how I knew about
all of it I see that's me that's quite a
position I didn't realize that you were
that higher rank you were telling the
director of the CIA what the rest of the
CIA wanted him to know that morning huh
yeah hey well just on that point how
much difference is there between the
truth and what you guys tell the
director what the truth is you know
because everybody it seems like
everybody out there wants their truth to
be known and you've got to be able to
read through the lines you've got to be
or between the lines I should say you've
got to be able to see what officer is
out there trying to promote himself to
get himself in front of the director and
telling you something that's patently
not true which happens every single day
let me tell you and then you know people
have a very short memory because I spent
seven and a half years as an analyst in
in the CIA's Directorate of intelligence
I had a longer term view of things than
than most operations people and so
somebody would say something about Iraq
for example you know with the Iraqis
have a nuclear program actually the
Iraqis don't have a nuclear program they
dismantled it and it's been confirmed by
the United Nations weapons inspectors
well they've only been on their job the
CIA people have only been on the job for
six months or 12 months they don't know
what the heck happened three years ago
with the UN weapons inspectors so you
need somebody who who's an institutional
memory and in the Directorate of
operations do you really don't have that
we have guys just clawing to get ahead
of each other
to recruit somebody to get face time
with the director so that they can get
promoted and become a station chief so
the truth the truth is the first
casualty I could see that the economics
of office politics but even worse in a
government bureaucracy let me say this a
CSCI a psychiatrist once told me that
the CIA actively seeks to hire people
who have sociopathic tendencies they
don't seek to hire sociopaths
because sociopaths have no conscience
they easily pass a polygraph and they're
impossible to control people who have
sociopathic tendencies do have a
conscience
but at the same time they are
comfortable working in moral or legal or
ethical gray areas the problem is it's
very easy for sociopaths to slip through
the cracks through the system and every
once in a while a psychopath will slip
through because again they're impossible
to control and hard to weed out and you
need dirty work done and you need dirty
work done and that's very attractive to
a lot of people and so not only are you
dealing with office politics but you're
dealing with CIA case officers who are
all alpha dogs by their nature and then
at the same time half of them are
sociopaths with no conscience so it's no
wonder that these things happen I think
the the amazing thing is that more
horrible things don't happen all right
hang on just one second for me hey guys
check it out I got a new sponsor it's
Hussein Badakhshan II author of the new
book no dev no ops no IT about how to
run your high-tech business correctly no
dev no ops no IT by Hussein Badakhshan
II it's on amazon.com also check out the
war State by Mike Swanson a great
history of the early rise of the
military-industrial complex after World
War two and also check out Mike's great
investment advice at Wall Street window
dot-com Robertson Robert's brokerage Inc
when you're ready to follow Mike's
advice and buy yourself some metals
that's rrb I see
our RBI CEO Liberty stickers comfrey or
anti-government propaganda
3t editing.com if you want your book to
read right somebody just sent me I was
coming from on Twitter this morning
there was a story of mando Weis about
how some settlers had chopped down a
bunch of olive trees on the west bank
and and someone said oh yeah merican and
Israelis shared values destroying
private property you know and it was
right when he sent me that was right
when I was reading in your article about
the Palestinian example or the the
Israeli example for why actually it is
okay to torture people as long as you
put it in a memo and you say that you're
trying to prevent worse harm and I'm
sorry I'm talking about Twitter but I
just like the guys response he said it's
another shared value we are the new
Machiavelli ins but with a twist the end
justifies the means but the end never
comes oh very very insightful that great
you know I had a guy when I was
stationed in Bahrain between 1994 and
1996 I had an intern working for me he
was a young kid from Yale you know what
I'm not even gonna use his name um and
he was really bright and he spoke Farsi
and I thought boy this this kids going
places and indeed he did go places he
ended up getting his PhD from Yale and
he became a major neocon thinker writer
and author major he very briefly did a
rotation not a rotation he very briefly
was chosen by the Bush administration to
work at the Pentagon and the run-up to
the Iraq war but I didn't even know he
was a neocon I ran into him at a
conference when I was the deputy
directors executive assistant and I said
hey why don't you come over to the
agency and you can break you can brief
the deputy director and the associate
deputy directors on what's going on in
Iraq so he came over and started talking
about I mean it was just this this
litany of neocon nonsense
in the run-up and then he capped it off
by by saying that one of the things that
he was recommending to defense secretary
Rumsfeld was a targeted assassination
program and I'm you could just see
people guffaw right so at the end of it
the deputy director said I think your
friends a little nutty and I walked him
out to the car and I said dude when did
you become a fascist and he says John
everything changed on 9/11 we've got to
take the bull by the horns you know
plaplapla and he's still out there
advocating targeted assassinations and
all these other different crimes against
humanity the shame of it is that it's
become mainstream and mainstream to the
point where a person like Donald Trump
can say that if elected he's going to
bring back waterboarding and quote a
hell of a lot worse so you know there's
been a real disservice in this country
by the neoconservative and neoliberal
movements that war is good war on our
Terms is better and we're just not going
to respect previous arrangements to
quote Junior soprano well the thing is
about it is tortures been illegal in
America since the Revolutionary War
General Washington said anybody who
tortures anybody I'll shoot you right
that's the order we executed Japanese
soldiers after World War two because
they had waterboarded American prisoners
of war in fact Ronald Reagan prosecuted
the Texas sheriff the DOJ I mean and
everybody knows any cop can commit any
crime and give me a break right but it
was ed Meese put a Texas sheriff in
prison for waterboarding a guy all that
torture and the law never changed you
know I say all the time in speeches that
in January of 1968 The Washington Post
ran a front-page photograph of an
American soldier waterboarding a North
Vietnamese prisoner and the day that
that picture was published the Secretary
of Defense ordered an investigation that
soldier was arrested he was prosecuted
on charges of torture and he was
convicted and sentenced to 20 years in a
military prison so torture was
in 1946 and it was illegal in 1968 but
then suddenly somehow it's not illegal
in 2002 despite the fact that the law
never changed
we changed but now okay so take me back
again you are now that I forget which
all title but you're the morning briefer
for the director and the deputy director
from which date to which date again yeah
from August of 2002 to August of 2003
mm-hmm so in the entire run-up to Iraq
war - yeah in the entire run-up in fact
I would I would go so far as to say that
90% of the information that I briefed
had to do with Iraq well and so are you
then confessing that you're the world's
greatest liar or you're saying you're
accusing the director of pretending to
not know the truth that you told him
which is it you know there's a funny
story that I told in my first book
between the reluctant spy we're on my
first day in that job I went up to the
associate deputy director and I said
okay I'm ready to go so what are we
doing and he said you know what I can't
even tell you what we're doing until you
go upstairs and sign your secrecy
agreements I thought that was odd but I
went up to the seventh floor knocked on
the appropriate door and said hey I'm
here to sign my secrecy agreements they
gave me six or seven different
agreements that I needed to sign
promising that I would never talk about
this information until the day I died or
until it was Declassified so it's been
Declassified and I signed the agreements
and I said to the guy okay so what's up
and he says here's the deal next year we
are going to invade Iraq we're gonna
overthrow Saddam Hussein we're gonna
install a pro US government in Baghdad
and we're gonna open the world's largest
Air Force Base in southern Iraq so that
we can move all of our air assets out of
Saudi Arabia and deprive Osama bin Laden
of the ability to say that we're
polluting the land of the Two Holy
Mosques
I was dumbfounded
and all I could think to say to the guy
was but we haven't caught bin Laden yet
and he kind of chuckled and he said
buddy the decisions been made and let me
tell you how this is gonna play out
he said battle lines have already been
drawn the pro-war side is the is OVP the
office of vice-president OSD the office
of the Secretary of Defense and the
National Security Council the anti-war
side is CIA which still wanted to hunt
bin Laden State Department and Joint
Chiefs of Staff
I began participating in these video
teleconferences with major players I
mean they were they were chaired by
either condi rice or Dick Cheney
depending on who was you know who was
available that day and every principal
and deputy were participating in these
things and I mean the battle lines were
clear in these video teleconferences
finally I was back benching George Tenet
one day and condi rice asked the Central
Command sink sent the commander-in-chief
of Central Command for a briefing on on
our plans to go across the Kuwait Iraq
border and he said well we have you know
X Y & Z divisions on the border we're
gonna attack day after tomorrow we're
gonna cross blah blah blah and then he
said we can be in Tehran by August and
George Tenet shut off his microphone
turned around to me because I was the
note-taker and he said did he say we
could be in Tehran or we could be in
Baghdad by August and I said he said
Tehran and he says have these people
lost their minds and then he turned back
around and turned his microphone back on
but this is what we were up against I
mean lie or no lie the fix was in from
the beginning don't forget that on
September 12th 2001 Richard Perle went
to the White House and told Condoleezza
Rice we have to attack Iraq so it really
didn't
matter if Iraq had weapons of mass
destruction it didn't matter if it
something or nothing to do with al-qaeda
the decision was made from the very
beginning of the Bush administration
that Saddam Hussein was going to die man
well great anecdote I mean I actually
have a part in the book where I quote
Paul Wolfowitz on the record saying
something a lot along those lines about
the motive for attacking Iraq and then
another anonymous quote which I think
may actually also be Wolfowitz both
saying that same thing where they're
basically you hear that everybody write
that the note of Ron Paul in there 9/11
happened because America was occupying
Saudi Arabia and we got to get those
bases out of Saudi Arabia it got us
attacked we want to deflate take the win
from bin Laden's sales by moving those
bases but then so what do they do
invade Iraq again million people and so
that yeah we got to be able to move
those bases to the north yeah they won't
mind died in though as long as the bases
aren't near Mecca and Medina which of
course Iraq just replaced the Saudi
bases on the list and there's still a
few bases in Saudi anyway so it makes
little difference but they actually
invoked blowback as the reason why they
needed to start a new war to miss just
two movies of damn bases a few hundred
miles north yep yep that's right and
listen you know I when I was an analyst
I was reading the Saudi press and I was
reading the al Qaeda you know
pronouncements I was reading all that
stuff and the complaints were that US
soldiers were having sex at the holy
Kaaba in Mecca that female soldiers were
walking around their bases naked and
after their their work day was over they
were going out into the towns and
working as prostitutes I mean you know
people who have no real exposure to the
United States or to Westerners they
believe this stuff the these allegations
have legs and the truth is it was better
for us and it would have been safer for
us just to not have anything to do with
Saudi Arabia we could have we could have
established forward position
we really needed them in Kuwait in
Bahrain in Qatar in the United Arab
Emirates in Oman all over the region we
have plenty of places all over the
region that we can base ourselves that
aren't Saudi Arabia and you know another
thing too Scott is and actually dr. Paul
mentioned this last weekend at the Ron
Paul Institute event in Dulles at Dulles
Airport he said that he said that we
really don't have a special relationship
with Saudi Arabia we say we do the
Saudis say we do but there's when you
cut cut right to the chase there's
nothing special about it we sell the
Saudis weapons and they sell us oil and
that's it there's nothing else this is
all about this is all about weapons
sales and capitalism and energy it's not
about a special relationship so if we
weren't dependent on Saudi oil and and
you know the truth is we're less and
less dependent every year a little bit
at least but if we want to power on
Saudi oil we wouldn't have any reason to
keep our bases in Saudi Arabia we could
just move them elsewhere
well we're not even really dependent on
Saudi oil I mean the whole thing is
really just a military strategy so in
case there's a war with China
we'll get yes we have the ability to
shut off their tap and we get all our
oil from Venezuela and stuff that's
right it is poured oil now yeah we do
again now ok so um all right we only
have a few minutes left here and well
you and I aren't done talking by a long
shot here but I'm not sure there's too
many different directions to go but I'm
gonna go with this one the other day you
and I together were interviewed by Kelly
Vallejos for the American conservative
magazines 9/11 video podcast special
thing there and you said this thing and
actually had a friend transcribe this
for me
Thank You Niko appreciate it you said
this to Kelly well and this is a little
bit out of time but I think it's same
difference anyway well the truth of the
matter is that the drone program is
probably the most potent recruiting tool
that foreign terrorist groups have I can
tell you that I interrogated dozens of
al-qaeda fighters
in my CIA years and to a man they all
said that they had no beef with the
United States they had no personal
problem with the United States until we
rocketed their villages with drones and
we killed their cousin or their parents
or their brother and sister or whatever
it was and they were compelled to take
up arms against the United States so
there are people in countries all over
the region not just in the Middle East
but South Asia and the Horn of Africa
that otherwise would never have had
reason to take up arms against us and
did so solely because of the drone
program so you know drone program is a
bit more specific but so I want to ask
you a couple of follow-ups from this
which is first of all can you help us
with the timeframe of when exactly you
were personally interrogating these guys
and then can you
I guess just verify that this isn't just
a figure of speech you really mean to
say to a man they all said that this was
about violence this was about Earth this
was not about my imam promise me virgins
in heaven if I only believe in radical
Islam hard enough and kill you for being
innocent or whatever right I'm talking
about 2002 to 2004 the early years of
the drone program but but I'll go even
even further than that there were others
who told me that they were how should I
say this they were they were residents
of isolated villages in their home
country whatever the country was doesn't
matter
Yemen Algeria Saudi Arabia whatever they
had no jobs no job prospects no
prospects for getting married they were
illiterate and what man would want his
daughter to marry someone who was
illiterate and had no job training and
so the local Imam went up to them and
said hey what are you doing staying
staying in this village you should go to
jail make jihad against the Americans
and if you do we'll give you 50 dollars
a month and if you're murdered we'll
give your family five hundred dollars as
a martyrdom bonus
and so you know they would go through
training and it was really no big deal
for them they didn't know the Quran they
had never read the Quran they didn't
know the prayers they weren't religious
really I mean they were Muslim but not
an economic draft is what you're talking
about that's exactly what it was that's
exactly what it was and what it comes
down to is they were they were really
not motivated to fight against us even
the ones who went through training
weren't really motivated to fight
against us but then we started killing
their families with drones or with
rocket attacks hey I went to I went to
Yemen in 2011 with the Senate Foreign
Relations Committee and it was my fifth
trip to Yemen over the previous 20 years
and every time I go to Yemen it's worse
than the previous time now it's a failed
state the whole place is in chaos I was
in a taxi and I said to the taxi driver
so how are things going with this Houthi
rebellion up north I've read that it's
it's getting pretty bad and he said yeah
the Houthis are dangerous but we're
confident of victory because the Saudis
are bombing them with drones and I said
the Saudis don't have drones and that
was the first time I had heard that we
were droning Houthi rebels in Yemen we
didn't have the Yemeni government's
permission to to fly drones armed drones
over their territory let alone to kill
Yemeni citizens and technically we're
supposed to be neutral in that war but
those had to have been our drones
killing those people up north see we dig
ourselves this hole and then we just
keep digging deeper and deeper and
deeper until we're at war and then we
can't get out of the hole we've dug well
that was what Hillary Clinton said was
when you look around you see all the
deep holes that we're in you figure
everybody better grab a shovel and get
digging stupid she never saw war she
didn't
jump right into yeah all right now so uh
oh man
I've only got one more second I'm gonna
keep you one more minute here Marc
Thiessen is this torture monger from the
Bush administration I forgot what his
position was in the bush mid-level
nobody he's at the American Enterprise
Institute yeah he was CIA then right is
that no a mid-level mid-level White
House nobody yeah white house yeah yeah
okay I'm sorry I was getting too
confused anyway so Thiessen he wrote a
thing in The Washington Post
and in the Washington Post he quotes
Mitchell the torturer the CIA contractor
torturers psychologist guy and so he
says contrary to what you may have heard
which I take as real progress for our
version of the narrative here contrary
to what you may have heard from the left
and the right bin Laden was definitely
not trying to lure us into a horrible
no-win quagmire of bankruptcy and
destruction like the Soviet Union no not
at all Mitchell says that colleague
Sheikh Mohammed told him that no geez we
thought you guys would pack up and run
away like after Beirut and after Black
Hawk Down and we were so surprised when
you came to invade and I thought you
know I don't know I guess it's possible
that Khalid Sheikh Mohammed and Osama
bin Laden never talked about this or is
it likely even maybe that Khalid Sheikh
Mohammed is just jerking Mitchell's
chain yeah and and and Mitchell is
reporting back jeez boss they say that
the last thing that they want is for us
to stay and spend every last dollar
we've got or or what do you think about
that you know teason is an idiot first
of all secondly Osama bin Laden said
publicly in audio tapes that he released
two aljazeera that the whole purpose of
the 9/11 attacks well it was twofold one
to punish the United States but the
other was to drag down the American
economy that was it he wanted to shut
down New York and shut down the stock
exchange and really damage the American
economy and at least in the short term
he succeeded and he told all this to
abdel bari at one
the all codes all IRB paper in London in
1997 or whatever I explained all of it
in depth he even said he was
disappointed when Bill Clinton left
after Black Hawk Down that was supposed
to provoke what he called a war of
attrition there and he didn't care how
many Somalis were supposed to die in the
thing he was wanting to get to replicate
in the battle against the Soviet Union
right there in 1993 when they first
tried to topple one tower into the other
you think somebody might have taken the
hint from that exactly anyway all right
listen I'm sorry I know you're out of
time we have a lot more talking about
two thousand two and three and the
run-up to Iraq I Langley headquarters
over there and I need to read your book
and so we'll be in touch thank you very
much John I look forward to it thanks
for having me always great to talk to
you Scott yes sir
all right guys that is John Kiriakou
who's the only CIA guy punished over the
CIA torture program for telling the
truth about it to a reporter really went
to the penitentiary for it and now he's
got this great new book it's well I
don't know how great it is but I bet it
is
it's co-authored with Joseph Hickman the
heroic whistleblower from Guantanamo Bay
about their Guantanamo quote suicides
there it's called the convenient
terrorist Abu Zubaydah coming out very
soon here I think it is oh no it is
already available right now and you can
read all about it at this great article
at salon.com
the road to torture how the CIA's
enhanced interrogation techniques became
legal after 9/11 by the both of them
there I'm Scott Wert and check out the
book it's fools air and time to end the
war in Afghanistan I cover a lot of the
same topics we just talked with John
Kiriakou about some of these paragraphs
that his block quotes are gonna be in
the next edition I'm pretty sure fool's
errand time down the war in Afghanistan
that's at fool's errand u.s. then you go
to Scott Horton org for all the
interview archives 4500 something
interviews going back to 2003 for you
there and I'm the managing director of
the libertarian Institute at libertarian
institute.org read the bad news at
anti-war calm and follow me on twitter
at scott wharton show thanks guys